https://www.comcare.gov.au/site-information/privacy

Entry into Comcare’s offices is restricted due to the COVID-19 situation. Find out how you can contact us during this time.
Site information
Privacy
Share this page:
Sitemap
Learn more about good workGet the latest national work health and safety news and evidence.Subscribe to Comcare eNews
Privacy
For: Claimants Employers and managers Service providers Advocates Information seekers
Your privacy is important to us and we are committed to the highest standards of privacy when we collect, store, use or disclose your personal information.
Steps we take to protect your privacyComcare is covered by national privacy legislation—Privacy Act 1988.The Privacy Act gives you rights including:to be told why your personal information is being collected and whether it can be given to anyone elseto see what information is held about you and have it correctedto have your personal information stored securelyif you believe your privacy has been infringed, you can make a complaint.Privacy Policy and actionsTo protect your privacy, we act to:ensure the personal information we collect, use, store or disclose is accurate, up to date and completemeet the requirements of the Privacy Act 1988, including the Australian Privacy Principles and Privacy (Australian Government Agencies) APP Code 2017 keep our privacy policy currentensure our staff understand and comply with their privacy responsibilitiesrespond to complaints quickly and honestlycontinue working effectively with the Privacy Commissioner.Our Privacy Policy (PDF, 369.1 KB) describes how we handle personal information and what types of personal information we generally hold. You can contact us to ask for the policy in another format.Privacy Impact Assessment RegisterA Privacy Impact Assessment is a tool to assist an agency understand and evaluate compliance with privacy principles.Comcare must maintain a register of all Privacy Impact Assessments completed, in accordance with s15(1) of the Australian Government Agencies Privacy Code.View the Comcare Privacy impacts assessment register.Personal information explainedSome common examples of personal information are:names, addresses, phone numbers or email addressesmedical certificates, clinical notes or medical reportspay slips or bank statementswitness statements.The Privacy Act 1988 defines personal information as: ’Information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable:whether the information or opinion is true or not, andwhether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not.Access or correct your personal informationYou can ask to access, amend or annotate the personal information we hold about you under the Privacy Act 1988. We aim to respond to your request within 30 days.email privacy@comcare.gov.aucall us at 1300 366 979.The Freedom of Information Act also supports personal information being amended if it is incorrect, incomplete, out of date or misleading.email foi@comcare.gov.aucall us at 1300 366 979.How to make a complaint about privacyYou can make a complaint to us if you believe we have interfered with your privacy or breached our obligations under the Privacy Act 1988:email privacy@comcare.gov.aucall us on 1300 366 979.Our Privacy Policy (PDF, 369.1 KB) provides more information on how to make a complaint and how we will respond.If you are not happy with our response or have a question about the Privacy Act or Australian Privacy Principles, contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.
Privacy statementsComcare eNews privacy statementSubscribing to Comcare eNews service is voluntary. You can update your subscription or unsubscribe from Comcare eNews at any time.Your privacy is important to us. We will only collect, use or disclose your personal information in accordance with the Privacy Act 1988 (Privacy Act).Comcare is the Commonwealth agency authorised by the Safety, Rehabilitation and Compensation Act 1988 (SRC Act) to do all things necessary or convenient to be done for, or in connection with, the performance of its functions under the SRC Act, Safety, Rehabilitation and Compensation Regulations 2019 and other legislation. Any personal information collected from this subscription will be used for those purposes and we will not share your personal information or disclose it overseas.For more information about how Comcare manages personal information, see our Privacy Policy (PDF, 369.1 KB), contact us on 1300 366 979 or email privacy@comcare.gov.au. Comcare’s Privacy Policy contains information including how people may access their personal information held by Comcare, how to seek correction of information, how to make a privacy complaint and how Comcare deals with complaints.Social media privacy statementWe use social media channels, including Twitter, LinkedIn and Vimeo, to communicate with the public about our work.When you communicate with us through these channels, we may collect your personal information, but we only use it to help us to communicate with you and the public.The social media services will also handle your personal information for its own purposes. These services have their own privacy policies. You can access the privacy policies for Twitter, LinkedIn and Vimeo on their websites.You can find out more information about how Comcare uses social media.
More informationPrivacy Policy (PDF, 369.1 KB)Privacy impacts assessment register.
Page last reviewed: 19 October 2020
You might also be interested in
Get updates from usSubscribeWorking during the Coronavirus pandemic. Subscribe to eNews to get advice from the national work health and safety authority.Subscribe to Comcare eNews
ComcareGPO Box 9905, Canberra, ACT 26011300 366 979 | www.comcare.gov.auDate printed 11 Dec 2020https://www.comcare.gov.au/site-information/privacy
